{
	"subject": "moral",
	"lesson": "l10",
	"grade": "c8",
	"quests": [{
		"id": 1,
		"question": "Who laid the foundation of Portuguese power in India?",
		"options": {
			"a": "Vasco da Gama",
			"b": "Vasco da Gama",
			"c": "Alfonso de Albuquerque",
			"d": "Almeida"
		},
		"answer": "c"
	}, {
		"id": 2,
		"question": "Which of the following European Nation was the foremost attempt to discover a sea route to India?",
		"options": {
			"a": "Dutch",
			"b": "France",
			"c": "Britain",
			"d": "Portugal"
		},
		"answer": "b"
	}, {
		"id": 3,
		"question": "In 1453 Constantinople was captured by ____________.",
		"options": {
			"a": "The French",
			"b": "The Turks",
			"c": "The Dutch",
			"d": "The British"
		},
		"answer": "b"
	}, {
		"id": 4,
		"question": "Sir William Hawkins belonged to ____________.",
		"options": {
			"a": "Portugal",
			"b": "Spain",
			"c": "England",
			"d": "France"
		},
		"answer": "c"
	}, {
		"id": 5,
		"question": "The first fort constructed by the British in India was ____________.",
		"options": {
			"a": "Fort William",
			"b": "Fort St.George",
			"c": "Agra Fort",
			"d": "Fort St. David"
		},
		"answer": "b"
	}, {
		"id": 6,
		"question": "Who among the following Europeans were the last to come India as traders?",
		"options": {
			"a": "The British",
			"b": "The French",
			"c": "The Danish",
			"d": "The Portuguese"
		},
		"answer": "b"
	}, {
		"id": 7,
		"question": "Tranquebar on the Tamilnadu coast was a trade centre of the ____________.",
		"options": {
			"a": "The Portuguese",
			"b": "The British",
			"c": "The French",
			"d": "The Danish"
		},
		"answer": "d"
	}, {
		"id": 8,
		"question": "Auto biography is one of the written sources.",
		"options": {
			"a": "True",
			"b": "False",
			"c": "",
			"d": ""
		},
		"answer": "a"
	}, {
		"id": 9,
		"question": "Coins are one of the material sources.",
		"options": {
			"a": "True",
			"b": "False",
			"c": "",
			"d": ""
		},
		"answer": "a"
	}, {
		"id": 10,
		"question": "Ananda Rangam was a translator served under British.",
		"options": {
			"a": "True",
			"b": "False",
			"c": "",
			"d": ""
		},
		"answer": "b"
	}, {
		"id": 11,
		"question": "The place where historical documents are preserved is called archives.",
		"options": {
			"a": "True",
			"b": "False",
			"c": "",
			"d": ""
		},
		"answer": "a"
	}, {
		"id": 12,
		"question": "The Dutch",
		"options": {
			"a": "1664",
			"b": "1602",
			"c": "1600",
			"d": "1616"
		},
		"answer": "b"
	}, {
		"id": 13,
		"question": "The British",
		"options": {
			"a": "1664",
			"b": "1602",
			"c": "1600",
			"d": "1616"
		},
		"answer": "c"
	}, {
		"id": 14,
		"question": "The Danish",
		"options": {
			"a": "1664",
			"b": "1602",
			"c": "1600",
			"d": "1616"
		},
		"answer": "d"
	}, {
		"id": 15,
		"question": "The French",
		"options": {
			"a": "1664",
			"b": "1602",
			"c": "1600",
			"d": "1616"
		},
		"answer": "a"
	}
]
}